Lu Yan
卢燕
Cheng Nu
程女
Have you seen anyone running out?
你见过有人跑出来吗？
There is a red birthmark on the face while wearing a hat
戴帽子脸上有红色胎记
Have you seen anyone running past you?
你见过有人跑过去吗？
He was wearing a hat and had a red mark on his face
他戴着一顶帽子，脸上有一个红色的印记
with red birthmark
带有红色胎记
I did not see it
我没看到
Cheng Nu
程女
did you see
你有没有看到
clam down
冷静下来
I'm really sorry
实在抱歉
sorry
对不起
Who did you see?
你看到谁了？
dead, dead
死了，死了
Another robot dies
又一个机器人死了
Someone died again
又有人死了
Where are you?
你在哪里？
Rubbish
垃圾
I heard it's the same as before
听说和以前一样
There are boards around, take me there, take me there
周围还有木板，带我去，带我去
Helped me walk around the store
帮我在店里逛了一下
go! go! go
去！去！去
let's see
让我们来看看
Another robot dies
又一个机器人死了
What a mess
真是一团糟
Why is there another one? Take a look
怎么还有一个？你看一下
Just asking you if you are afraid
就问你怕不怕
What about the excitement you promised?
说好的激动呢？
Look at the paintings on this earth.
看看这个地球上的画作。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
This is Android
这是安卓系统
Contact the recycling department
联系回收部门
Let people regain their bright eyes
让人们恢复明亮的眼睛
When did people die?
人什么时候死的？
So how do I know?
那我怎么知道呢？
I also saw it when I came here
我来的时候也看到了
Someone died a few days ago
前几天有人死了
Isn't this another kind of death?
这不是另一种死亡吗？
Are there any other Android devices?
还有其他安卓设备吗？
Yes I have
是的，我有
right there
就在那里
take me there
带我到那里
he goes
他走
This is where people are found
这是人们被发现的地方
where was found
在哪里发现的
I really don't know this yet
我真的还不知道这个
but i heard what they said
但我听到他们说的话
when the body was found
当尸体被发现时
Now there is only one breath left
现在只剩一口气
It was also put into a very strange shape
还被摆成一个很奇怪的形状
There are many pictures and texts drawn next to it
旁边画了很多图片和文字
Anyway, it's weird
无论如何，这很奇怪
Have you met this person?
你见过这个人吗？
Take a closer look
细看
There is a red birthmark on his face
他脸上有一个红色的胎记
don't like it that much
不太喜欢它
Is he a murderer?
他是凶手吗？
minister
部长
Where is the young girl?
青女在哪里？
I'm not sure
我不太确定
Why are you acting alone again?
怎么又一个人行动了？
What's wrong? What's wrong?
怎么了？怎么了？
Today we met someone on the old street
今天我们在老街上遇见了一个人
Lu Yan called
陆彦打来电话
Qingnu continues to chase him
青女继续追赶他
I asked him who he was, but he didn't answer me.
我问他是谁，他没有回答我。
Minister, you know this man
部长，你认识这个人
After meeting Lu Yan
遇见卢燕后
Cheng Nuo's whole situation is very strange
程诺整个情况很奇怪
I know this is his private matter
我知道这是他的私事
But I think as a partner
但我认为作为合作伙伴
We must have basic confidence
我们要有基本的信心
I should know him better
我应该更了解他
The mother of the young girl Chang Ya
青女常雅的母亲
Once upon a time, a bright-eyed Android researcher
曾几何时，一位目光明亮的安卓研究员
Lu Yan is one of her partners
卢燕是她的合伙人之一
but
但
but a year ago
但一年前
Zhang Ya committed suicide by jumping off the building
张雅跳楼自杀
And before she died
而在她去世之前
The last call was made to Lu Yan
最后一个电话是打给陆颜的
after her death
她死后
Lu Yan
卢燕
also missing
也失踪了
The four victims did not know each other.
四名受害者互不认识。
no common friends
没有共同的朋友
Even if I live far away
即使我住的地方很远
These four cases have two things in common:
这四个案例有两个共同点：
first
首先
All victims are robots
所有受害者都是机器人
second
第二
After the murderer committed the crime
凶手犯罪后
He will leave your twin horoscope on the spot
他会在现场留下你的双胞胎星座图
same murder ritual
同样的谋杀仪式
same way of working
相同的工作方式
Basically it can be judged as a serial crime.
基本上可以判定为连环犯罪。
There are some things in common
还有一些共同点
They are all related to Lao Jie
都和老杰有关系
Are you OK
你好吗
Chen Xinhui has nothing to do with Lao Jie, right?
陈新辉跟老杰没有什么关系吧？
Not important at first glance
乍一看并不重要
But I checked
但我查了一下
When Fang Yuan’s mother bought it,
方媛妈妈买的时候，
Just on the old street
就在老街上
How would the murderer know?
凶手怎么会知道？
They are all Android
他们都是安卓的
The murderer may be interested in Lao Cai's robot business
凶手可能对老蔡的机器人业务感兴趣
I understand very well
我很明白
So we guess
所以我们猜测
The murderer is probably a resident of Laoji
凶手很可能是老吉的居民
The environment on the old street is a mixed bag.
老街上的环境鱼龙混杂。
Our work
我们的工作
may be difficult
可能很难
Even if you walk from house to house
即使你挨家挨户地走
I want to take it out too
我也想拿出来
Auntie, have you seen this person?
阿姨，你见过这个人吗？
go! go! go
去！去！去
I am bright-eyed detective An Qiu
我是明眸侦探安秋
We're investigating two Android murders
我们正在调查两起 Android 谋杀案
I have never met anyone as good as you.
我从来没有见过像你这样优秀的人。
Do you know this person?
你认识这个人吗？
Have you met this person?
你见过这个人吗？
Many stray cats and dogs die every day
每天都有很多流浪猫狗死去
show me
给我看看
Do you know this person?
你认识这个人吗？
Isn't this the robot that died nearby?
这不是死在附近的那个机器人吗？
Have you heard of this?
你听说过这个吗？
I've never seen this before, have you seen this photo?
我以前从未见过，你见过这张照片吗？
I do not recognize
我不认识
No impression at all?
一点印象都没有吗？
Really not
真的不
Buy a bird?
买只鸟？
Hello, have you met this person?
你好，请问你见过这个人吗？
No impression, no impression
没有印象，没有印象
unprecedented
前所未有
Have you met this person?
你见过这个人吗？
I ask you if you know this person
我问你是否认识这个人
may i know your name
我可以知道你的名字吗
I said what's your name
我说你叫什么名字
I asked what your name is
我问你叫什么名字
welcome
欢迎
Her name is Qiu
她的名字叫邱
And you
你呢
Hello, my name is An Qiu, and you are
你好，我叫安秋，你是
It's your name, isn't it?
这是你的名字，不是吗？
Your name is Yihang
你叫一航
Did you draw all these pictures?
这些图都是你画的吗？
What is the name of this painting?
这幅画的名字是什么？
Moulin Rouge ball
红磨坊球
Red
红色的
So what are you painting now?
那你现在画什么呢？
Now
现在
Cheng Nu
程女
Qingnu, who painted this?
青女，这是谁画的？
Qingnuo is you, right?
青诺就是你吧？
Where is this person in the painting?
画中这个人在哪里？
Look at the young girl
看看青女
What's your job
你做什么工作
Who are you?
你是谁？
Your son went to the scene where the robot was killed.
你儿子去了机器人被杀的现场。
Maybe it has something to do with this
或许和这个有关
Lopsided
渐行渐远
My son has nothing to do with this
我儿子与此无关
It doesn't matter
没关系
No problem, no problem
没问题，没问题
It's okay, Yihang
没关系，一航
Nice painting
画的不错
Don't leave, come back
别离开，回来吧
Why are you cursing my son?
你为什么咒骂我儿子？
What evidence do you have?
你有什么证据？
Cheng Nuo goes first
程诺先行
Go quickly
快去
Are you late enough?
你够晚了吗？
It's no use at all
根本没用
He must be autistic
他一定是自闭症患者
Originally, communication with the outside world already existed
本来，与外界的沟通就已经存在了
Did you hear what he said?
你听到他说的话了吗？
He said there was a lot of blood
他说有很多血
Lu Yan was also present
陆颜也在场
Most likely they are together
最有可能的是他们在一起了
Kill the robots you know.
杀死那些你认识的机器人。
I heard
我听说
you need to calm down
你需要冷静下来
you are completely out of control
你完全失控了
I'm calm
我很冷静
I don't need you to teach me
我不需要你来教我
I'm very sorry
我很抱歉
I've caused you a lot of trouble
我给你带来了很多麻烦
Actually I don't know
其实我不知道
How to take care of this child
如何照顾这个孩子
Is what I just said true?
我刚才说的是真的吗？
We're not sure yet
我们还不确定
But the person we're looking for
但我们要找的人
This is one of Yihang’s paintings
这是一航的画作之一
We doubt
我们怀疑
He is a killer robot
他是机器人杀手
I always feel like I know my kids very well
我总觉得我很了解我的孩子
But sometimes I think it's weird
但有时我觉得这很奇怪
I still don't understand
我还是不明白
Why Yang
为什么是扬
appear in every painting of yours
出现在你的每一幅画中
add yourself to it all
将自己添加到这一切中
if he doesn't
如果他不这样做
Where could there be so much trouble?
哪里会有这么多麻烦？
per panel
每个面板
Would you like to add yourself to all of this?
您愿意将自己添加到所有这些中吗？
look
看
of course i hope
我当然希望
Yihang has nothing to do with this matter
亿航与此事无关
But only by finding the truth
但只有找到真相
Only in this way can we really help him
只有这样我们才能真正帮助他
Do you know where he could go?
你知道他能去哪里吗？
a trip
一趟
Don't worry
不用担心
I'm just asking you some questions
我只是问你一些问题
Can I just answer truthfully?
我只要如实回答就可以吗？
I said this afternoon
我说今天下午
What does heavy bleeding mean?
大量出血意味着什么？
lots of blood
大量的血
correct
正确的
Yihang, look at me
一航，看着我
Have you ever harmed a robot?
你伤害过机器人吗？
harm robot
伤害机器人
There is another trip, go check it out
还有一次旅行，你去看看吧
Who taught you to draw that painting?
谁教你画那幅画的？
who painted it
谁画的
Yihang, look at me
一航，看着我
Who taught you to draw that painting?
谁教你画那幅画的？
dyeing
染色
Is he the person in the painting?
就是画里的那个人吧？
One trip, one trip
一趟，一趟
a trip
一趟
Cheng Nu
程女
What's your job
你做什么工作
He is not a killer
他不是杀手
I saw him paint that painting with my own eyes
我亲眼看到他画那幅画
If he is not the murderer
如果他不是凶手
How do you draw a scene where a body is thrown?
你如何画出尸体被扔的场景？
many details
很多细节
This is his talent
这就是他的才华
He can imitate other people's paintings
他可以模仿别人的画
can also be accurately
也可以准确地
draw what you see
画出你所看到的
Well, in the afternoon he said he was bleeding a lot.
嗯，下午他说他流了很多血。
exactly what this means
正是这意味着什么
Qingnu, please calm down first.
青女，你先冷静一下。
Yihang usually wanders around the ancient streets.
一航平时就在古老的街道上闲逛。
I've heard others say
我听别人说过
Previous Android system
之前的安卓系统
Just lying in the alley like this
就这样躺在巷子里
Next to the trash can
垃圾桶旁边
Maybe Yihang saw him
也许一航看到了他
so i drew them
所以我画了它们
Yihang may be an eyewitness
一航可能是目击者
It's the same in the painting
画里也是一样的
You told me he was a witness
你告诉我他是证人
He integrates himself into every painting
他把自己融入到每一幅画中
He wants everyone to know him
他希望每个人都认识他
He wants everyone to know
他想让所有人都知道
All the paintings were painted by him
所有的画都是他画的
This is all your guess
这都是你的猜测
Even if he is a witness
即使他是证人
Then why didn't he mention who the person in the painting was?
那他为什么不提画里的人是谁呢？
Where
在哪里
Do you really want to find the murderer?
你真的想找到凶手吗？
What does it mean
这是什么意思
Your mother committed suicide
你妈妈自杀了
Will finding Lu Yan change this ending?
找到陆颜会改变这个结局吗？
Yes
是的
The result cannot be changed
结果无法改变
but i just want to know
但我只是想知道
Does my mother's death have anything to do with me?
我母亲的死与我有什么关系吗？
birthday every year
每年生日
she works
她工作
Gradually
逐步地
I don't care about celebrating her birthday with her
我不在乎和她一起庆祝生日
You no longer have any extravagant hopes
你不再有任何奢望
but
但
I was fifteen years old that year
那一年我十五岁
She even remembered my age wrongly
她连我的年龄都记错了
compared to me
与我相比
She is more interested in studying robots
她对研究机器人更感兴趣
She studied hard and got into a prestigious school
她努力学习，考入名校
All for her to see me
一切都是为了让她看到我
Mom, I'm accepted
妈妈，我被接受了
MIT
麻省理工学院
OK
好的
This is a full scholarship
这是全额奖学金
i know you will be accepted
我知道你会被接受
But no matter what I achieve
但无论我取得什么成绩
In her eyes, everything seemed normal.
在她眼里，一切都显得很正常。
robot to some extent
机器人在某种程度上
More paranoid and extreme than us
比我们更加偏执和极端
But I think they still have a chance to improve
但我认为他们还有进步的机会
Give up famous schools
放弃名校
Be a keen-eyed detective
做一名目光敏锐的侦探
This time, I want
这一次，我想
She can take me seriously now
她现在可以认真对待我了
I even did this
我什至这样做了
Be prepared to be scolded by her
做好被她训斥的准备
If you have any questions, you can come to me anytime
如果有什么问题可以随时来找我
Yes
是的
You're welcome
不客气
Teacher Chang
常老师
Cheng Nuo came to our department
程诺来我们科室了
why are you here
你为什么在这
Friends, let’s talk first
小伙伴们先说说
What's the situation now?
现在是什么状况
I'm not going to MIT
我不会去麻省理工学院
I want to work here
我想在这里工作
I also want to study Android
我也想研究一下安卓
your life
你的生命
make your own decision
自己做决定
What's your job
你做什么工作
go away
走开
Cheng Nu
程女
money loss
金钱损失
Let me go
让我走
Why fight robots?
为什么要与机器人作战？
they will get hurt
他们会受伤
you only care about them
你只关心他们
Did you see that I was hurt too?
你看到我也受伤了吗？
Qingnu, you have grown up
青女，你长大了
independent
独立的
You have to learn how to calm down
你必须学会​​如何冷静下来
Instead of hurting the robot
而不是伤害机器人
to vent dissatisfaction
为了发泄不满
Since you like Android so much
既然你这么喜欢安卓
Why did you give birth to me?
你为什么生下我？
Let these robots be your children
让这些机器人成为你的孩子吧
she has
她有
I've always been redundant
我一直都是多余的
So I blocked her phone messages
所以我屏蔽了她的电话信息
Then she disappeared from her world
然后她就从她的世界消失了
until that day
直到那一天
This is your mother's body. Please sign it.
这是你母亲的遗体，请在上面签名。
Don’t you hate Android?
你不讨厌安卓吗？
only you
只有你
you want your mother's attention
你想要你妈妈的关注
I always say she doesn't care about me
我总是说她不关心我
but i don't actually care about it
但我其实并不关心它
I didn't even know she had depression
我什至不知道她有抑郁症
Until the last words I said to her
直到我对她说的最后一句话
They both allowed the robot to become her child.
他们都允许机器人成为她的孩子。
Do you still remember Yihang’s paintings?
你还记得一航的画吗？
Lu Yan's paintings
卢彦的画作
Just wear this necklace
只要戴上这条项链
Xia Qing
夏清
you know her
你认识她
Lu Yan's wife
卢燕的妻子
He died in a car accident a year ago
他一年前因车祸去世
where do you find it
你在哪里找到它
Rubbish
垃圾
give me your hand
把你的手给我
I am fine
我很好
do not move
别动
More than two hours have passed
已经过去两个多小时了
Lu Yan hasn’t come yet
陆颜还没来
maybe he won't come
也许他不会来
I guess
我猜测
maybe so
也许是这样
It’s your psychological analysis again
又是你的心理分析
No analysis required
无需分析
Everyone wants to get back what they lost
每个人都想找回失去的东西
you are always awake
你永远醒着
I can not sleep
我无法入睡
Thanks
谢谢
stop staring and walk away
停止凝视并走开
Why
为什么
I've been waiting all night
我已经等了一整晚
he won't come back
他不会回来
Can your body handle it?
你的身体能承受吗？
I am fine
我很好
forgotten
忘记了
Wait until you are cold and then rely on me
等你冷了再依赖我
let's go
我们走吧
Are you worried about me?
你担心我吗？
wait a little longer
再等一会儿
Why
为什么
You've been staring at me for a long time
你已经盯着我看了很久了
I don't care about this moment either.
我也不关心这一刻。
Go to sleep, I'll watch over you
快去睡觉吧，我会看着你的
Cheng Nu
程女
he came
他来了
He will run away later
稍后他会逃跑
Don't worry yet
先别担心
What he is looking for is in our hands.
他要找的东西就在我们手里。
Better to wait and see where it goes
最好等等看它会走向何方
Believe me
相信我
clear
清
What’s wrong with you
你怎么了
there is nothing
没有什么
No wonder I can’t find Lu Yan
难怪找不到陆颜
It turns out he is hiding here
原来他就藏在这里
he goes
他走
OK
好的
I'm leaving now
现在我要走了
almost
几乎
Cheng Nu
程女
Do you know Lu Yan?
你认识卢燕吗？
Then why did he lock you up?
那他为什么要把你关起来？
It's okay if you don't want to say it
如果你不想说也没关系
Lu Yan killed someone
陆颜杀了人
and kidnapping of teenagers and children.
以及绑架青少年和儿童
Now let’s collect the stolen goods together
现在大家一起收赃
when he comes back
当他回来时
Put him directly in jail
直接把他关进监狱
Uncle Lu Yan is a good man
陆彦叔叔是个好人
You can't catch him
你抓不到他
children
孩子们
Jain
贾恩
why are you here
你为什么在这
Why kill these robots?
为什么要杀死这些机器人？
I didn't kill them
我没有杀他们
then your necklace
然后你的项链
Why did he appear in the burial ground?
他为何会出现在尸葬场？
Where is my necklace?
我的项链在哪里？
give to me
给我吗
Do you want to say it or not?
你想说还是不想说？
I didn't actually kill those robots.
我并没有真正杀死那些机器人。
Yesterday I met you on the old street
昨天我在老街上遇见了你
That's because I just heard someone died
那是因为我刚刚听说有人死了
That's why I went to take a look
所以我才去看看
How to explain these three children?
怎么解释这三个孩子呢？
you can go now
你可以走了
these three children
这三个孩子
They were all street children I met along the way.
他们都是我一路上遇到的流浪儿童。
I help them find foster homes.
我帮助他们找到寄养家庭。
I haven't really killed anyone.
我真的没有杀过任何人
The last time my mother called
妈妈最后一次打电话时
What was said specifically?
具体说了什么？
Do you really think so?
你真的这么认为吗？
Did Zhang Ya commit suicide?
张雅是自杀吗？
What does it mean
这是什么意思
She can't commit suicide
她不可能自杀
Shortly after the Android recall was announced
就在Android召回宣布后不久
Founded by Zhang YaA
张亚A创立
Robotics Research Laboratory
机器人研究实验室
After the laboratory was established, I...
实验室建立后，我...
Just joined
刚刚加入
I'm from Mingmo headquarters
我是明墨总部的
Apply for collection of human body electronic information
申请采集人体电子信息
Thanks to Dr. Zhang for the research
感谢张博士进行的研究
She said she wanted to try psychotherapy
她说她想尝试心理治疗
Find and destroy the robots
找出并消灭机器人
main obsession method
主要痴迷方法
Let them better integrate into human society
让他们更好地融入人类社会
But not long after
但没过多久
Zhang Ya suddenly called and said
张雅突然打电话说
Stop research project
停止研究项目
She asked me to go to the lab to find her
她让我去实验室找她
But I didn't find it in the lab
但我在实验室没找到
from
从
But I saw this number
但我看到了这个数字
Leave the lab
离开实验室
So why not chase it?
那为什么不去追呢？
this time
这次
Dr. Zhang Ya falls from building
张亚医生坠楼
I just want to keep
我只想保留
What I put in the safe
我放在保险箱里的东西
This is electronic body data about to be investigated.
这是即将接受调查的电子人体数据。
Her story remains a secret
她的经历仍然是个秘密
Have you seen what it looks like?
你见过它是什么样子吗？
Why did the murderer take her away?
凶手为何要带走她？
he
他
Quiet
安静
this list
这份清单
I haven't given it to Dr. Zhang yet.
我还没给张医生呢
Later I heard that many androids died.
后来听说很多仿生人都死了
Then I investigated
然后我调查了
found dead
被发现死亡
All from the same batch
全部同批次
Robots deliver dazzling headquarters
机器人交付亮眼总部
So you go to the dump
所以你去垃圾场
To confirm the identity of the deceased
为确认死者身份
I've been looking for you this year
今年我一直在找你
Why are you hiding this from me?
你为什么要瞒着我？
Why do you run when you see me?
为什么一看到我就跑？
Zhang Ya passed away
张雅去世
I didn't hide it from you on purpose.
我不是故意瞒着你的。
it's because of fear
这是因为恐惧
afraid of what
害怕什么
Don't know the murderer's purpose
不知道凶手的目的
But it must have something to do with the laboratory
不过肯定和实验室有关系
after all
毕竟
I'm also involved
我也参与其中
kill me and silence me
杀了我并让我沉默
it's just a matter of time
这只是时间问题
These robots are in the list
这些机器人在列表中
Are these two the only ones left alive?
难道只剩下这两个人还活着吗？
that's all i can tell you
这就是我能告诉你的一切